# Linette Maliakal

http://linmaliakal.com lmaliakal@luc.edu | 847.401.9237

# **EDUCATION**

# LOYOLA UNIVERSITY CHICAGO

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Expected May 2020 | Chicago, IL Presidential Scholarship (All Years) Dean's List (2016 - 2017) Cum. GPA: 3.60 / 4.0 Major GPA: 3.70 / 4.0

### LINKS

GitHub:// linmaliakal LinkedIn:// linette-maliakal Twitter:// @linmaliakal

#### COURSEWORK

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Scientific & Technical Communication Operating Systems Human Computer Interaction Software Development: Wireless & Mobile Devices Client-Side Web Development Database Programming Software Engineering (Research Assistant)

# **SKILLS**

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Java • JavaScript • HTML5 CSS3 • Python • LATEX C++ • PHP • Assembly Familiar:

iOS • Android • Windows OS MySQL • XAMPP • MongoDB Firebase • InDesign • Canva Microsoft Office • Prezi IntelliJ • Android Studio • Eclipse

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish • Malayalam

#### SUMMARY

Who am I? A geeky software engineer with 3 years of experience coding in Java and 2+ years of experience with UI/UX design and development using HTML5/CSS3 & JS. Asked by founders of Brave Initiatives to speak on behalf of them at their fundraiser.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### GIRLS WHO CODE | VOLUNTEER

August 2018 - Present | Chicago, IL

 Aid 20+ girls in developing their website projects, teaching them the meaning of various tag elements and how to design their sites well, assisting them to solve error code in HTML/CSS/JS

# **DON'T PANIC! CS** | SECRETARY & COMMUNICATIONS COORDINATOR August 2018 - Present | Chicago, IL

- Help coordinate meeting times for majority group members to attend, collect information from new members, record notes from meetings
- Develops hackathon attendance as group, in charge of communications through email
- Tends and keeps Twitter account @dontpanic\_CS up to date

# NORTHWESTERN SMARTCAR HACKATHON | PARTICIPANT

February 2019 | Evanston, IL

• Develop phone application using Cordova framework and Smartcar API as well as various Google APIs for a service to assist roadside car trouble

#### BRAVE INITIATIVES | Coding Instructor/Coach Intern

May 2018 - September 2018 | Chicago, IL

- Taught coding curriculum for HTML/CSS/JavaScript at Brave Camp, a design thinking & coding camp that empowers high school girls to be agents of change in their local communities.
- Walked the girls through building their own websites with basic web development skills.
- Worked with teams for each week and guided them to think creatively through their ideas and execute them in their sites

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **CAMPFIRE** | Backend/Frontend Developer

September 2018 - December 2018 | Chicago, IL

Led team and divided tasks to complete for cross-platform mobile application, using the Cordova framework, that connected individuals in the area for event meet-ups. Was awarded the faculty vote and a monetary compensation at Loyola CS Department Semester Celebration.

### **AWARDS**

2018 1st Faculty Vote CS Department Semester Presentations

## SOCIETIES

2018 National Alpha Phi Omega Service Fraternity